記不記得Carmen教授跟我們說了上個禮拜的事
記不記得上個禮拜
是有人被耶穌醫治 是不是
他有什麼問題 記不記得
What problem did this person have
什麼問題
中文是什麼 Carmen
麻瘋 是不是
It is leprosy
Leprosy是很contagious的 是不是
所以他們之前覺得
他一碰到 或者在同一範疇
Leprosy的那一個人
他們就會被感染
是不是 好像我們COVID那時候
有沒有人沒有戴口罩
很歡迎這個COVID 是不是
很歡迎
Come COVID come
是不是
不是 因為你保護你自己
You wear a mask
You wear gloves
你有沒有看到美國那些
購物 買購物
他又有個Astronaut suit
又有高利貸口罩
全部是全身穿著的 是不是
去機場有沒有人
有個全身穿著口罩的
其實我試過
因為我有些Dental friend
他就給我眼鏡
那些全身口罩去機場
上機 是不是
We are afraid of disease
Pastor Carmen 上個星期跟我們說了
Jesus is greater than any disease
Jesus is our lord and savior
他不會被disease影響的 是不是
Leprosy很重要
You lose your senses
你現在打擊那些senses
你的thumb fingernail
Imagine 沒了sense
Maybe it's good for those who are
I'm joking
因為Jesus說
If your leg causes you to sin
Or your arm causes you to sin
I'm just joking
沒了sense
又沒了鼻子的sense
又沒了腳的sense
因為they have no sense
So they have no pain
So they keep getting injured
So that is what is happening
今天我們會繼續
The healing of Jesus
我們會讀Luke 5
Let's read this together
Let's read English together
1, 2, 3
One day
OK 耶穌是做很多奇妙
跟著這裏
Let's go to the news of Jesus slide
News of Jesus slide
跟著他們寫
Luke是這樣寫
The power of the lord was with Jesus to heal
那你一聽到
有沒有人想神去醫治你
Anybody want some sort of healing
可能是ADHD
可能是depression
可能又physical
咬柴又injury
You want God to heal you
那你之前呢
醫生啊
Physio 是不是很available
耶穌的年代
Is it readily available
It's not
不是每個角落都有醫院
好像香港那樣
So when they hear of a solution
Of a miraculous solution
他會怎樣
He will line up
你有沒有看到那些人
Line up for 什麼
香港是line up for 什麼
Food 買東西
買鞋
Pokemon card
或者入學校
有些人父母都要排隊
People line up
So you can imagine
如果耶穌在這個時代
這裡沒有醫院
很少醫生
And then there is a solution
Jesus is the solution
He is a miraculous healer
誰會排隊
Who will line up
你幫你婆婆
阿姨叔叔
你幫你阿姨叔叔排隊
會不會
Would you
You would
And so that is what he was saying
Everybody from every town and village
Galilee to Jerusalem
To Judea
個個都排隊去見
去見耶穌
個個都想有healing
Everybody wants to be healed
有一次耶穌在一間屋
他在一間屋
很多人
有些朋友帶誰來
A paralyzed man
Next slide
OK
A paralyzed man
A paralyzed man是動不了的
OK
這個是
這個paralyzed man
有沒有人
有沒有人看過一些video
這些人是paralyzed的
他們可不可以自己生存的
Can they
It's very hard
是不是
他動不了
那要wheelchair
之前有沒有wheelchair
It was very difficult
When was wheelchairs invented
你可以Google
Alright
可能沒有wheelchair
You relied on the goodness of your friends
of your family 去幫你
是不是
如果你是paralyzed
你今天paralyzed
誰會幫你
Who are the four friends in your life
that would help you
Lincoln
If you are paralyzed today
Who would help you
Would Elias help you
You think so
真的會
他可能打機
然後不記得你
You be careful
是不是
If you are paralyzed today
Who are your four friends
that would help you
你想想
Who are your four friends
這個paralyzed person
就被四個friend
去帶去哪裏
去meet Jesus
The friends want him to be healed
Who want him to be healed
他去找耶穌的時候
多不多人
爆了場
你看next slide
都進不到這間屋
他進不到這間屋
他的解決方法是什麼
Okay
如果你是paralyzed man
的四個friend
What would you do
Imagine
耶穌在這裏中間
是不是
很多人
想讓他被醫治
爆了場
爆到去MTR station
那裏要排隊
你覺得你會怎樣
你會怎樣
如果你是那些四個friend
Yeah
Wow
你有讀聖經嗎
有讀經文嗎
Wow
Okay
That is exactly
他們的選擇是什麼
他們的四個friend的選擇是什麼
What are the options
Leave
這麼多人
在MTR exit B那裏
都排到去那裏
Can you imagine
怎樣進去找耶穌呢
We can't
還有什麼選擇
Okay
Mine a hole
在這裏的window
Okay
Try again next time
You can leave
You can try again next time
Or you can find a solution
這個四個friend
可能是engineer
誰想讀engineering
是不是
他們就在rooftop那裏
Imagine the rooftop
是不是
他break down some tiles
然後他lower
How do they find rope
Somehow
他們有一個pulley system
是可以lower
可能他們是攀石那些人
他們懂得lower
他有個belay device
四個belay device
慢慢可以lower
他們的friend
into the middle of the room
Imagine
into the middle of the room here
To meet Jesus
我們看到
這四個friend
是faithful friends
是不是
他上天台
lower them
Right
他們come up with a solution
第一我們看到
他們是compassionate
他們compassionate
They care about their friend
They care so much
They are willing to break the tiles of the roof
and lower them down
他們
這四個friend
是合一的
They are united to do this together
不是一個說好
一個又說我要走了
一個就說太難了
No
他們是合一
to lower the friend together
合一
你有沒有四個friend
是合一去幫你的
或者
Are you one of the four friends
that would be willing to help somebody
that is in need
還有
他們是persistent
很多人
找不到耶穌
不要緊
我們會繼續找解決方案
Persistent
Would you persistently help your friend
我們今天會學四個F
四個F
第一
是faithful friends
第二
是faith-filled friends
Faith-filled friends
Four
No.3
Forgiven before healing
還有第四
Faith over doubt
四個F
OK
Let's continue reading
Luke chapter 5 together
我們讀中文
OK
1,2,3
第一個F
是faithful friends
Faithful friends
他們很loyal
Persistent
United to help
第二
是faith-filled friends
Faith-filled friends
為什麼耶穌去heal這個人
為什麼耶穌說想heal這個人
因為他們看到了他們的信仰
誰是他們的信仰
朋友的信仰
他們有沒有信心
他們很有信心耶穌可以heal他們的朋友
這就是他們經歷了一切
通過群體
破壁
降低了朋友
降低了他們的朋友
他們信誓旦旦地相信
耶穌可以醫治他們
當耶穌看到了他們的信仰
他們的信仰
你四個朋友
是不是很有信心
去為你祈禱
去帶你去耶穌
你有四個信誓旦旦的朋友嗎
這麼有信誓旦旦地會帶你去耶穌
你有四個有信誓旦旦的朋友嗎
這四個朋友
是主動去帶他們去認識耶穌
他們是有破壞性的信念
破壞性的信念
如果我們裝修
如果現在上面裝修
搞錯了他們裝修
我們現在有sermon的時間
你遲一點才裝修
你imagine
耶穌和他的人
在一個房間
然後有人break down the tiles
break down the tiles
弄塌了roof
然後lower的人
那些房間的人會不會抱怨
我們少少construction
聲音都會抱怨
弄塌了lighting speaker
然後lower一個paralyzed man
into this room
你說騷不騷擾
very disruptive
為什麼他們這麼disruptive
because they had so much faith
that Jesus would heal their friend
do we have disruptive faith
我不是叫你很disrupt
你問問你的mentor好不好
或者你的pastor好一點
問問你的pastor
is it a good idea first
disruptive faith
requires great wisdom
great wisdom
and they were bold
they were very bold
and so faith filled friends
initiative disruptive and bold
之前為什麼我們introduce
saturday service
因為我們好有信心
that God wants to build you up
and make you men and women of God
and this fast food service
is not gonna help
這個fast food service
你早上又起不到身
然後國語堂又什麼時候走
我們要進來
然後爸爸媽媽又等你吃飯
fast food service is not gonna help you
we are faith filled leadership team
that believe that this saturday service
will really help you to grow
we wanna give you the full time
full attention
full space to grow
這個不是我們不想
星期日這麼早
我們好懶
no that is not the reason
the reason is because we are
faith filled leadership team
that are willing to take initiative
to have disruptive faith
to be bold and step out for Jesus
and say we believe this is
the best for you guys
你明不明白
we are faith filled leadership team
我們可以continue
這個sunday service
fast food sunday service
不用have a town hall meeting
同mentor講
同你的parents講
同你們講
no we can just live our happily life
sunday is routine
but we want what is best for you
we are the four friends
that want you to grow
你明不明白
明不明白
me, pastor carmen, winnie, sam
we are the four friends
that want to help you to grow
明不明
yes
and that is why
Jesus is giving us this message today
that is why Jesus is giving us this message today
第一個F是什麼
記不記得
Faithful friend
Are you a faithful friend
No
OK
So we all need improvement
第二是什麼
Faith filled friend
Faithful
Faith filled
第三
Forgiven before healing
耶穌就這樣講
Friend, your sins are forgiven
The pharisees said this
Oh sorry
Who is this fellow who speaks blasphemy
Who can forgive sins but God alone
The pharisees
The teachers of the law
就challenge耶穌
Your sins are forgiven
你的罪是forgiven
How
誰可以赦免你的罪
Who can forgive your sins
Who
你的mentor可以赦免你的朋友嗎
你啊,赦免你啊
可以,如果你得罪他可以
But who can forgive your sins
Your mentor cannot
Your pastor cannot
因為我們有自己,我們也有罪
是不是
But who can forgive you of your sins
The only one who is without sin
And that is who
誰沒有罪
耶穌是沒有罪
Not Muhammad, not Gandhi
Not Muhammad, not Donald Trump
Definitely not Donald Trump
OK
他可以赦免你
But he cannot forgive you of your sins
That is a big difference
明白嗎
OK
Forgiven before healing
耶穌是realized
Yes
這個paralyzed man has a physical need
But he has an even greater spiritual need
And that is the healing of his soul
The healing of his soul
Do we recognize
可能我們的身體有軟弱,有問題
We need physical healing from Jesus
But what is even more at need
Is our spiritual healing
我們個個是有犯罪的
我們個個都有impure thoughts, selfish thoughts
我們個個是得罪了人
得罪了耶穌,得罪了神
We have all fallen short of the glory of God
And we need spiritual healing
And with this healing, with this word
Jesus is identifying himself
As Lord and Savior
Lord and Savior
好,我們讀一讀
Luke Chapter 5
Let us read Luke Chapter 5 together
OK
Let's read together in English
One, two, three
Jesus knew what they were thinking and asked
Why are you making these things for us
Which is easier to say
Your sins are forgiven
Or to say get up and walk
But I know that the Son of Man
Has authority on earth to forgive sins
So he said to the paralyzed man
I tell you, get up, take your mat and go home
Immediately he stood up in front of them
Took what he had been laying on
And went home praising God
Everyone was amazed and gave praise to God
They were filled with awe and said
We have seen remarkable things today
好,耶穌就問這個問題
這個問題是
What is easier
Your sins are forgiven
Or get up and walk
哪個比較容易
好,我們進入我們的討論群組
你旁邊那些
Let's go to the discussion question
The first question is
What is easier
Your sins are forgiven
Or to say get up and walk
哪個比較容易
Which is easier
第二,這個問題是
What do you think is Jesus' main message
好,我們四分鐘可以分享
Ok,誰覺得
Your sins are forgiven is easier
誰覺得
Because you can just say
Oh, I chose
It's easier to say your sins are forgiven
Because you can just say it
But then if you say get up and walk
It might be like false
And they can't actually get up and walk
Ok,Louis的觀點是
你可以就這樣說
Your sins are forgiven
沒有人知道
是嗎?So it's easier
Ok,有沒有人覺得
Get up and walk is easier
Ok,your explanation
Ok,我就覺得有兩個觀點
可能在人的角度來說
你的聚社了
比你起來行走
是容易一點
Because it's just 一句說話
但是在神
可能在神學的角度來看
你起來行走是難一點
Because it requires a miracle
第二就是
你認為耶穌透過這個訊息
想說什麼
可能就是
神想說的就是
人的根源
是我們的罪
而不是我們身體的疾病
而身體的疾病只不過是
表面上的一些東西
Ok,給點掌聲
Louis
Anybody else?
還有沒有人想說的?
Anybody else want to share?
Med student
What is your perspective?
我覺得你的聚社了難一點
因為你起來行走
這件事是
你醫生都做到
或者人都做到
但是沒有人可以
因為可以定罪的
只有權柄高過你的人
可以寫罪的
都是只有權柄高過人的人
所以
失去就難一點
Ok, thank you Andrew
我們給點掌聲Andrew
Talk versus results
這個是talk versus results
你可以很容易說
我很厲害
我踢球很厲害
我可以入很多球
But the results will show
whether you're really good or not
是不是?
Josea是很謙虛的
I think he's our top goal scorer
Ok?
但是有些其他的
是很吵的
覺得自己很厲害的
但是很少說的
是不是?
That's the thing
Talk versus results
Actually Donald Trump talks a lot
But he also does a lot
Would you agree, Uncle Vincent?
He actually does a lot
每個國家都有tariff
整個list都是
不同的百分比
全部都是
我也不知道他怎樣找百分比
是不是?
Talk versus results
So which is easier?
當然是healing is easier
In terms of
Sorry
Talk, which is easier?
Your sins are forgiven
But easier
Sorry
In terms of results, which is easier?
Talk is easier
Because you can't check
Just like Louis said
Ok?
So
In terms of results
Sorry, did I mess this up?
再說一次
如果你只是說話
Which is easier?
當然是your sins are forgiven
沒有人check到
是不是?
But in terms of
doing the actual thing
Healing or forgiving sin
哪個是?
Forgiving sin
No one can forgive sin
是不是? 剛才Andrew說
醫生也可以
是不是?
There's many solutions to healing
但是赦免罪
There's only one solution
And that is Jesus
Ok,四個F
Faithful friends
Forgiven before healing
We need spiritual healing
Yes, our physical
We have physical need
And limitations
But what is greater
Is our spiritual need
And the last thing is
Faith over doubt
But I want you to know
That the son of man
Has authority on earth
To forgive sins
So I said
So he said to the paralyzed man
I tell you get up
Take your mat and go home
Here Jesus is revealing
That he not only has power
And authority over the physical realm
He has power and authority
Over the spiritual realm
Jesus is king over the universe
Whenever we have faith
There's going to be somebody
That challenges us
耶穌是不是真的
你的healing
是不是真的耶穌heal你呢
還是你自己coincidence
There's always going to be those
Who challenge you
你成績好
是不是真的神幫你呢
你帶你去這個job
是不是真的神帶你
還是幸運而已
There will always be doubt
People will always challenge us
As Christians followers of God
But we need to stand firm
In who Jesus is
We need to stand firm
Based on our building
Our own personal relationship with him
Right
不是只是人家說就信
No we need to find Jesus ourselves
我們好像paralyzed man
可能我們自己行不到去
有朋友帶我們去
有沒有朋友帶我們去Jesus
There are four key lessons from today
The four key lessons are this
Are we faithful friends
我們有沒有帶
我們的朋友去Jesus
Who is on our mat
Who is in our life
That needs spiritual healing
Maybe physical healing as well
And we can help them
Through the power of Jesus
第二個question
Are we faith filled friends
我們是不是好像那四個朋友
很有信心
Go through any barrier
Any obstacle
We still lead our friends to Jesus
可能我的朋友是atheist
可能我的朋友是有一個bad experience from church
It doesn't matter
I will still pray for them
I will still be persistent
To help them know Jesus
我們是不是faith filled friends
That will lead others to Jesus
第三是
Do we seek forgiveness over healing
我們之前說了
我們個個都有physical limitations and weaknesses
但最重要是我們的靈魂
有沒有給神去forgive我們的sin
這才是最重要的
你有找到耶穌嗎
你有尋求祂的原諒嗎
和祂的靈性治癒嗎
最後一個問題
當教會團隊提出的時候
我們有信心
在耶穌的權力
在物質和靈性範圍內嗎
我們有百分之百的信心
耶穌可以治癒
祂在我們身邊
祂可以原諒我們
因為祂在兩千年前死了
我們有沒有信心
耶穌是我們
可以赦免我們
我們有信心
耶穌可以原諒我們我們的罪嗎
我們來一會
我們把頭垂下來
把頭垂下來
我們就像一個被困住的人
我們無法幫助自己
我們對手機很沉迷
對地圖很沉迷
我們無法分辨真與假
我們被困住了
我們需要一個救贖
來赦免我們的罪
今天有人想要耶穌的赦免嗎
可以把手舉起來
我們來祈禱赦免
也許你走錯了路
也許你做錯了事
你傷害了別人
你需要耶穌的赦免
你需要祂的赦免嗎
如果是的,把手舉起來
我們為你祈禱
在我們說這句祈禱時,請跟著我說
親愛的耶穌
我感謝祢在兩千年前死在我的腿上
你被刺傷了手臂和腿
你的身體為我的罪犯犧牲了
我感謝祢是我的主人和救贖
我歡迎祢在我的生命中
赦免我的罪
在耶穌的名字下,我祈禱
Amen